Indra Lesmana

Android Developer



PHONE +6285956736630

EMAIL

indra953@gmail.com

Profile

I have 3 years of work experience as an Android Developer. I Have developed several applications including digital banking, digital transportation, point of sales with custom device and custom bill, movement location tracking and mapping to google earth KML, fintech implement OCR, realtime chat using SendBird SDK and payment integration (Dana, Gopay using Midtrans) etc. I am interested in developing applications that become public service facilities.

Employment History

Apr 2020 - Present

JAKARTA

Android Developer

Home Credit Indonesia

Home Credit, a multipurpose financing company that provides financing services for customers in shopping online and offline.

Client: PT Home Credit Indonesia

Responsibility:

- · Help team to develop app from new project
- · Work together with team using Jira, gitlab, and scrum

May 2019 - Present

JAKARTA

Android Developer

PT Xdana Investa Indonesia

X Saver

Xdana is an investment application in the field of mutual funds, to facilitate users in saving

Responsibility:

- · Help team to maintain app
- · redevelopment older apps with new android technology

Published: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.xdana.cash

Sep 2016 — Apr 2019

BANDUNG

Android Developer

PT. WGS

Xdana Cash

Xdana is an investment application in the field of mutual funds, to facilitate users in saving

Client: PT Xdana Investa Indonesia

Responsibility:

- · Help team to develop app from new project
- · Work together with team using trello, gitlab, and scrum

Trans Hybrid

Trans Hybrid is a company's internal application for the maintenance and installation of corporate optical cable networks such as marking locations of fiber optic damage, sharing photos of damage, mapping fiber optic cable path planning and etc.

Client: PT. Trans Hybrid Communication

Responsibility:

- · Help team to develop app from new project
- · Work together with team using trello, gitlab, and scrum

BRI konsumer

Is an internal application for BRI employees to submit KPR, credit cards, loan simulations and customer assessments

Client: PT. Bank Rakyat Indonesia

Responsibility:

- · Extended team to develop feature and fixing bug
- · Work together with engineering team (20+ member) using trello, gitlab, gsheet

Published: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=id.co.bri.brispotkonsumer

Dipostar

Is an application that makes it easy to calculate credit for all car products sold by the company

Client: PT. Dipostar Finance

Responsibilty:

- · Help team to develop app from new project
- · Work together with team gitlab, Apiary, gsheet

Ezytopup reseller

Is a game voucher sales application using SUNMI devices (Android with integrated printer) to facilitate companies in making dynamic vouchers for resellers

client: Rajagame

Responsibility:

- · Help team to develop app from new project
- · Work together with team gitlab, Apiary, gsheet

Biyu

is an application for recruiters and people in the entertainment world to meet each other, recruiters offer jobs or post jobs with certain talent criteria.

Client:-

Responsibility:

- · Help team to extend and continue development
- · Work together with team using trello, gitlab, and scrum

Medictrust

is an application to make it easy to record a medical history that is directly connected to the doctor

client:-

Responsibility:

- · help team continue development
- · Work together with team using trello, gitlab, and Dropbox

Published: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.medictrust

Jan 2017 - May 2019

BANDUNG

Android Developer

Freelance

Sejalan

May 2018 - May 2019

Is an application that makes it easy for users to meet driver who have the same direction

Client: PT. Astra Digital International

Responsibility:

- · Help team to develop app from new project
- · Work together with team using trello, gitlab

Published: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=id.astra.adp.sejalan

Movic

Is an application that makes it easy for users to rent car

Client: PT. Astra Digital International

Responsibility:

- · Help team to add feature
- · Work together with team using trello, gitlab

Published: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=id.astra.adp.movic

Tiket Pesawatnya

is a plane ticket application that makes it easy for users to purchase airplane tickets

Client:-

Responsibility:

· add some features and fixing bugs

Published:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.tiketpesawatnya.tiketpesawatnya

Education

Dec 2012 - Dec 2016

STMIK LPKIA

BANDUNG

Bachelor's Degree in Informatics Engineering

Major: Teknik Informatika

CGPA: 3.09 / 4.00

Skills

Android Development

Unit Test

Kotlin

Java

RX Reactive

00P

Git

Consume API

Gitlab CI/CD

Courses

Oct 2018 - Dec 2018

Kotlin Android Developer Expert

Dicoding

Jul 2017 - Sep 2017

Android Developer Fast Track

Google []

Hobbies

Watching Documenter film and play console game